# João Victor Torres Borges

## **Robotics Engineer**

🔀 Rio de Janeiro-RJ, Brazil

+55 8299801 5259

https://borgesjvt.github.io

https://github.com/BorgesJVT

borgesjvt@gmail.com

# Languages

Portuguese

**English** 



# Skills

C++

Python

ROS/ROS2

Git

OpenCV

O PyTorch

Linux

Docker

Robotics

**Computer Vision** 

Control Systems **Embbeded Systems** 

Machine Learning

# **Open Source Contri**butions -

ros2 control

ros2 control demos

I'm a Computer Engineer graduated from the Federal University of Alagoas, Brazil. I have acted as Robotics Engineer for +2 years professionaly, and a couple more years of academic experience, working with Control Systems, Navigation, Simulation e SLAM. I also have worked with Computer Vision and Embbeded Systems on projects of Mobile Robots and Autonomous Systems applications, with emphasis on Underwater Robotics on the latest projects. My strong skills are C++ and ROS for development. Currently, I work at the Research Institute of Brazilian Navy.

# **Working Experience**

#### **Fulltime**

2019 - 2021 **Robotics Engineer**  SENAI CIMATEC

**Digisub** is a project of a Underwater Sensor Scanner for 3D Point Cloud object reconstruction to attend tasks of inspection for the Oil and Gas sector. Activities developed were the implementation of a camera driver and to improve the software robustness for testing in the field.

RBiM is a project of a UAV to attend tasks of inspection and intervention for the Oil and Gas sector. Activities developed were the robot dynamic model in an underwater environment, controller design, teleoperation and control of devices. An interface for debugging and data visualization was also implemented.

TRIS project - Thermal Remote Identification System of Feverish People raises up, during COVID-19 pandemic, as a virus propagation control tool by assisting in the process of detecting feverish people. The essential modules are face detection and recognition, as well as, temperature estimation. Activities developed were the software architecture design, data acquisition and integration of modules into an optimized pipeline for real time application.

2019 – 2019

**Robotics Engineer** 

**Brisa Robotics** 

Activities developed were software development and integration, mainly stacks like mapping and localization, navigation and WEB dashboard, to launch a differential robot capable of navigate autonomously.

Demo work: https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity: 6554061159870316544/

## **Education**

2022 **Computer Vision Nanodegree** 

Udacity

Image Segmentation, CNN Layers and Feature Visualization, YOLO, RNN Layers, Kalman Filter, SLAM.

2011 – 2017

**Bachelor in Computer Engineer** Federal University of Alagoas - UFAL Thesis: A Case Study for Analysis and Evaluation ORB-SLAM Algo-

Demo work: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7BjP0osEKhU&t=

# **Publications**

2020 TRIS: Thermal Remote Identification System of Feverish People

International Symposium on Innovation and Technology - SIINTEC

PID Controller Synthesis for Network Controlled Second Order 2018

Systems

Brazilian Conference on Automation - CBA